<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- -*- coding: utf-8;-*- -->
<Infoproblemtype version="1.0">
  <Program>
    <Name>kratos</Name>
    <Version>1.0.7317</Version>
    <MinimumGiDVersion>11.1.5d</MinimumGiDVersion>
    <ImageFileBrowser>images/Classic/ImageFileBrowser.gif</ImageFileBrowser>
    <ShortDescription>Kratos - Kratos is a framework for building multi-disciplinary finite element programs. It provides several tools for easy implementation of finite element applications and a common platform for natural interaction of the same in different ways.</ShortDescription>
    <Description>
    * What is Kratos?

    Kratos is a framework for building multi-disciplinary finite element programs. It provides several tools for easy implementation of finite element applications and a common platform for natural interaction of the same in different ways.
    
    Kratos is an innovative variable base interface designed and implemented to be used at different levels of abstraction and to be very clear and extendible. A very efficient and flexible data structure can be used to store any type of data in a type-safe manner. An extendible IO is also present to overcome a bottleneck in dealing with multi-disciplinary problems and the major interpreting task is given to the Python interpreter.
    
    The kernel and application approach is used to reduce the possible conflicts arising between developers of different fields and layers are designed to reflect the working space of different people also considering their programming knowledge.
    * Who may use Kratos?
      
    Some potential users of Kratos are:

     - Finite Element Developers: These developers are considered to be more expert in FEM, from the physical and mathematical points of view, than C++ programming. For this reason, Kratos provides their requirements without involving them in advanced programming concepts. 

    - Application Developers: These users are less interested in finite element programming and their programming knowledge may vary from very expert to higher than basic. They may use not only Kratos itself but also any other applications provided by finite element developers, or other application developers. Developers of optimization programs or design tools are the typical users of this kind. 

    - Package Users Engineers: and designers are other users of Kratos. They use the complete package of Kratos and its applications to model and solve their problem without getting involved in internal programming of this package. For these users Kratos has to provide a flexible external interface to enable them use different features of Kratos without changing its implementation. 

    * Who is Kratos?

    The Kratos structure, due to its multi disciplinary nature, has to support the wide variety of algorithms involved in different areas. That's the principal reason that explain the variety of people, mostly engineers, composing the Kratos Community.

    * Keywords

    Free Multi-physic Finite Element Method C++ Open Source Code

    Kratos is MULTI-PHYSIC. One of the main topics in engineering nowadays is the combination of different analysis (thermal, fluid dynamic, structural) with optimising methods in one global software package with just one user interface and, even more, the possibility to extend the implemented solution to new problems.
    
    Kratos is FINITE ELEMENT METHOD (FEM) based. Many problems in engineering and applied science are governed by Partial Differential Equations (PDE), easily handled by computer thanks to numerical methods. The FEM is one of the most powerful, flexible and versatile existing methods.
Kratos is OBJECT ORIENTED. An integration of disciplines, in the physical as well as in the mathematical sense, suggests the use of the modern object oriented philosophy from the computational point of view. The modular design, hierarchy and abstraction of these approaches fits to the generality, flexibility and reusability required for the current and future challenges in numerical methods. 
Kratos is OPEN SOURCE. The main code and program structure is available and aimed to grow with the need of any user willing to expand it. The GNU Lesser General Public License allows to use and distribute the existing code without any restriction, but with the possibility to develop new parts of the code on an open or close basis depending on the developers.

Kratos is FREE because is devoted mainly to developers, researchers and students and, therefore, is the most fruitful way to share knowledge and built a robust numerical methods laboratory adapted to their users' needs. Free because you have the freedom to modify and distribute the software. The one thing you're not able to do with free software is take away other people's freedom. Please, read the license for more detailed information. 
      </Description>
    <NewsInVersion version="1.0.7" date="2013-07-05">
      * this is the first GiD-internet retrieve version with Kratos 3.2.7135. it uses an internally distributed version of the python interpreter. Compiled with ubuntu 12.04 LTS on X86_64
      * ...
    </NewsInVersion>
    <ValidatePassword>
    </ValidatePassword>
    <MsgcatRoot>msgs</MsgcatRoot>
  </Program>
</Infoproblemtype>
